<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOME on Oscar De Alva</title>
    <link>https://oscardealva.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HOME on Oscar De Alva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Oscar De Alva</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:45:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oscardealva.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviwer for Reddit</title>
      <link>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/reviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:53:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/reviewer/</guid>
      <description>A simple React Native application which let&amp;rsquo;s the user browse Reddit and save desired posts to a relational database hosted in Heroku. It was developed using the TypeScript byndings for React Native 0.61.5 along with the data models of the application and the REST requests to Reddit and the database server.
The database server was developed using JavaScript ES6 with Node.Js/Express in order to expose a simple REST API that the application connects to in order for the data to be saved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Engine for Cranfield Collection</title>
      <link>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/search_cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 16:22:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/search_cran/</guid>
      <description>A search engine that was based upon the Inverted Index technique along with the Boolean Retrieval Model for querying the Cranfield Test Collection.
The Scala programming language was used for the implementation of the mentioned techniques. Also, the Scala Parser Combinators library was used for creating a parser and a language that allowed to successfully read both the test collection and the user&amp;rsquo;s query.
For the parser&amp;rsquo;s query, the AND, OR and NOT boolean operations were implemented, along with their precedence, and the usage of parenthesis to group together operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetris</title>
      <link>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/tetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 16:13:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/tetris/</guid>
      <description>A Tetris Clone developed in Java using Swing for the User Interface.
A leveling system was implented where pieces will fall of faster depending on the level, increasing the difficulty. Also, a scoring system was implemented along with most of the sound effects of the game.
Gradle was primarily used for creating a JAR of the application that contained all the images and sound effects used.
It was developed as the final project for Graphics and Animation course (Lis3021).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Reservation System</title>
      <link>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:03:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscardealva.com/portfolio/classroom/</guid>
      <description>A classroom reservation that allows users to show the classrooms that are reserved, their schedule and by whom it was reserved. It also shows the active periods of the current semester and the subjects that are active for the semester.
Scala was used to implement the system, along with its Swing library to develop a desktop interface. The application conects to a local database in PostgreSQL, using Doobie for handling the connection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>